
<problem>
    <script>
from math import factorial as f
from math import ceil
from math import sqrt
from math import exp
from math import log
from math import erf
import random

def C(n,m):
    return f(n)/f(m)/f(n-m)

def myrandom(start,stop,step=1):
    return random.randint(0, int((stop - start) / step)) * step + start

def Phi(x):
    #Cumulative distribution function for the standard normal distribution
    return (1.0 + erf(x / sqrt(2.0))) / 2.0

def Q(x):
	return 1-Phi(x)





n = myrandom(10,20,1)
score = myrandom(570,589,0.5)

ans1 = Q((score-509)/112.0)

newdev = 112.0/sqrt(n)
ans2 = Q((score-509)*1.0/newdev)




answer1 = 1.0*ans1
answer2 = 1.0*ans2
answer3 = "0"


</script>
<p><br/>
Scores for men on the verbal portion of the SAT-I test are normally distributed with a mean of 509 and a standard deviation of 112.<br/>
(a) If 1 man is randomly selected, find the probability that his score is at least $score.<br/>
<numericalresponse answer="$answer1">
                    <responseparam type="tolerance" default="1%" />
                    <formulaequationinput />
                </numericalresponse>
</p><p><br/>
(b) If $n men are randomly selected, find the probability that their mean score is at least $score.<br/>
<numericalresponse answer="$answer2">
                    <responseparam type="tolerance" default="1%" />
                    <formulaequationinput />
                </numericalresponse>
</p><p><br/>
(c) As more and more men are randomly selected, the probability that their mean score is at least $score approaches <formularesponse type="ci" samples="m,n,i,k,x,y,z@1,1,1,1,1,1,1:10,10,10,10,10,10,10,10#10" answer="$answer3">
                    <responseparam type="tolerance" default="0.00001"/>
                    <formulaequationinput />
                </formularesponse>
</p><p><br/>
(d) Two students are debating this diminishing tail probability is a consequence of which statistics law. <br/>
Student A argues that the <b>Law of Large Number (LLN)</b> explains this behavior because this is basically what the weak LLN states.<br/>
Student B argues that <b>Central Limit Theorem (CLT)</b> explains this behavior because as \(n\) gets larger the Gaussian gets more concentrated and the tail gets smaller. <br/>
Having heard both arguments, which of the following statements do you think is correct ?<br/>
<multiplechoiceresponse>
  <choicegroup label="Which of the following statements do you think is correct ?" type="MultipleChoice">
    <choice correct="true">Just the Law of Large Number is sufficient</choice>
    <choice correct="false">LLN is not enough, we also need Central Limit Theorem to justify this behavior</choice>
  </choicegroup>
</multiplechoiceresponse>
</p><p><br/>
</p>
</problem>