
<problem>
    <script>
from math import factorial as f
from math import ceil
import random

def C(n,m):
    return f(n)/f(m)/f(n-m)

def myrandom(start,stop,step=1):
    return random.randint(0, int((stop - start) / step)) * step + start







answer1 = "2/3"
answer2 = "1/3"
answer3 = "2/3"
answer4 = "1/3"
</script>
<p><br/>
<br/>
This probability puzzle is weakly related to a game on an old TV show called _Let's Make a Deal_, and has been renamed after the host of that show. The host brings the game player to a room with three closed doors. One of the doors leads to a treasure chest while the other two doors each lead to a goat. The player picks a door (at random, presumably), hoping for the best. Now something interesting happens. Instead of opening that door, the host opens one of the other two doors to reveal a goat. The player is then allowed to either stick to his original guess, or to switch to the other unopened door. Which should he do?<br/>
In surveys, the majority of people feel intuitively that it doesn't make a difference. They reason that there are two unopened doors, and the treasure could be behind either of them, so each has a 50-50 chance of being the lucky door. But this is incorrect. The player should switch to the other door: by doing so, he will double his chances of getting the treasure! A conditional probability calculation shows why:<br/>
\(<br/>
\begin{align*}<br/>
P(\mbox{treasure in other door}) <br/>
 = <br/>
P(\mbox{treasure in other door} | \mbox{initial guess correct}) P(\mbox{initial guess correct}) + \\<br/>
  P(\mbox{treasure in other door} | \mbox{initial guess wrong}) P(\mbox{initial guess wrong}) \\<br/>
 = <br/>
0 \cdot \frac{1}{3} + 1 \cdot \frac{2}{3} <br/>
\ \ = \ \ <br/>
\frac{2}{3} .<br/>
\end{align*}<br/>
\)<br/>
o What is the probability the first door the contestant picks has a goat behind it?<br/>
<formularesponse type="ci" samples="n,m@1,1:20,20#10" answer="$answer1">
                    <responseparam type="tolerance" default="0.00001"/>
                    <formulaequationinput />
                </formularesponse>
<br/>
o What is the probability that switching doors will get you a goat?<br/>
<formularesponse type="ci" samples="n,m@1,1:20,20#10" answer="$answer2">
                    <responseparam type="tolerance" default="0.00001"/>
                    <formulaequationinput />
                </formularesponse>
<br/>
</p>
</problem>